Good afternoon, everyone. How are you
all keeping?
It's really good to see you. You all
look beautiful. You look really great.
Um
It's so good to be here. It's so good to
be here. Um thank you so much. I'm so
grateful. Um
Graduands, families, supporters,
academics, professional service staff,
vice chancellor, pro vice chancellor,
and so on.
I hope you're all well, my dear friends.
Thank you so much for having me here
today. It truly is an honor to be in
your precious and distinguished company,
and I'm beyond grateful.
My love affair with this place began
some 24 years ago when I was 15, when my
school when my school at the time
arranged an off-site sports day at St.
Mary's.
So, to be stood here in front of all of
you today is beyond surreal.
You all look wonderful, and I'm bursting
with pride and happiness for you all.
Please try and take this day in.
The first time you graduate is
definitely the most It's definitely one
of the most best days of your life.
I would like to thank the honorable vice
chancellor, Ann Tie McCarran, for
conferring this honor upon me. I've been
immensely fortunate to have received
many accolades throughout my adult life,
but given my affinity to this particular
place, this one possibly means the most.
I'm absolutely humbled, honored, and
moved, and this means more to me than
you'll ever know. I would I would to
extend my greatest thanks to Rachel
Bowles and Emma Thomas for their efforts
in logistically getting me, my friends
and family here today.
Congratulations, class of 2024.
What you have achieved today is
remarkable in very challenging and
uncertain times.
I'm in awe of your tenacity, brilliance,
and resilience. You have demonstrated
something truly special in your three
years, and it's my greatest aspiration
to be as great as you one day.
You all have the power to do such great
and good in this world.
Use your gifts to change the world and
think about what you can do to make this
world a better place through the
vehicles of love, compassion, and care.
I've pretty much spending most of my
life losing to win.
So, there is something quite ironic and
funny about being here today.
I was never the most academically
gifted. I was never the most intelligent
person, and I was never the one they
said would come good.
At the French Open at Roland Garros at
Philippe Chatrier Court,
there's an expression which adorns the
court from the former ruler of France,
Napoleon, and it reads,
"Victory belongs to the most tenacious."
I would like you today to remember this
and to always remember this.
Will will always supersede skill, and if
you are fortunate to possess both like
you all are,
please use it to mobilize the greater
good.
I was very much disowned and always
rejected, but I was determined that in
the ultimate I would not be denied. I
was flanked by the unwavering support of
a few people, and while I always knew I
had a level Sorry, and while I always
knew that I had modest levels of skill
when I first started, I always had the
will. It was always a case of will
versus skill.
Skill can always be measured, my
friends, but will is immeasurable.
The tenacity is something you all have
in abundance, and in addition to your
extraordinary levels of skill, I can't
emphasize how proud I am of all of the
graduates here today.
My own journey demonstrates that with
faith, hard work, and humility, anything
is possible.
If you want to learn to be a good
winner, you have to be able to lose with
exceptional grace.
Your gifts far surpass mine, and I
cannot emphasize how in awe I am of all
of you. But always remember that hard
work beats talent when talent does not
work hard. Use your gifts wisely and
with humility, and again with regards to
the greater good, use your brilliance to
change the world.
No person is an island, and I've been
blessed to have been I've been blessed
to have met some of the most wonderful
people the world has to offer to support
me in my journey to this point, and I'd
like to acknowledge them today.
I would like to extend my deepest thanks
to anyone that has ever extended a kind
word or prayer to me. It's been humbling
and gratefully received, and that has
comforted me in times of doubt.
Especially Dr. Chantel Jessica Lewis,
Paulette Williams, Debbie McKenzie,
Laura Morton, and Andrew Simmons, who
actually was the person who taught me
how to write in the first place when I
got to university.
So, Andrew Sandry, you've been the
biggest influence on my adult life, and
quite simply, I would not be here if it
were not for you. The time you invested
in me and the belief you had in me at
the age of 18 years of age proved to be
the most similar intervention in my life
and provided a catalyst for us to take
on the world and win.
I would like to thank my mother and
father, Gifty and Joseph Addai, who
taught me all the values I try to
faithfully embody today.
Your love, sacrifice, and belief has
been unwavering, and I'm extremely lucky
to be your son.
There are two people that I would like
to dedicate this honor to.
Both these two people are the most
extraord- are two of the most
extraordinary human beings.
Both have left an indelible imprint on
St. Mary's and have been instrumental in
mobilizing students and ensuring that
all students are valued and provided the
best conditions to thrive.
One of these people is the coolest
person I've ever met. I often say
talking about this person, it was like
love at first sight.
In their time as interim head
of well-being and disability, in their
time as
Sorry, let me start again. In their time
as interim head of well-being and
disability service manager
at this great institution, they
implemented a wide range of pastoral
services aimed at supporting students'
mental health and well-being. Perhaps
more importantly than this, this person
has always believed in the potential of
human beings and the importance of
empathy, compassion, and understanding.
This person is like a brother to me and
one of my oldest friends.
Michael Charles Cobden,
thank you for everything you have done
for me
over the last 20 years.
Sorry.
I love you very much, and after all this
time, you're still the coolest person I
know.
The other is the most remarkable human
being I have personally ever met.
What truly makes this individual
entirely unique is that for 30 years,
pretty much every member of the St
Mary's family, staff, and students alike
would say the same thing.
In a world of continuous change, this
person has always provided stability.
She has been a home, friend, and a
mother to thousands of students,
including myself.
As head of student services, this person
has literally saved countless lives.
Her outstanding contribution to higher
education was recognized in 2017 by the
late Queen Elizabeth II with a British
Empire Medal.
Beyond accolades,
we are all truly lucky to still have her
in this world.
Sorry.
The good you have done for others all
your life,
the care and compassion and love you
have shown people is the true embodiment
of what St Mary's is all about.
Sue Witton, quite simply, you are St
Mary's, and you have been like a mother
to me and thousands of students over the
past three decades decades.
There are not enough words to express
how much I love you. Thank you for
everything you've done for me over the
past 20 years and throughout my time
here in my adult life. You are the best
of the very best and the mold was
definitely broken after they made you. I
dedicate this honorary doctorate to both
Michael and Sue. You both deserve this
and thank you for everything.
I would like to thank God for everything
and blessing me with the privilege and
honor of being here with you today to
share in your amazing achievement.
Seeing you all prosper in this way means
more to me than anything as you
represent the very best of the future.
Thank you to all the professional
service staff and academics that have
supported graduates to this point over
the last couple of years and the
domestic staff and security staff who
have created the best environmental
conditions for you to thrive in.
And finally, I would like to send the
biggest thanks of all to the parents,
carers, supporters at graduation today
who cradled your hopes, dreams, and
fears. The sacrifices your parents,
carers, and families will have made will
not be lost on those of you that are
that are will not be lost on those of
you in terms of the success you enjoy
today. Congratulations to you all.
Keep the faith
and never give up.
Always feed the faith and starve the
fear. You are all great beyond measure.
Humanity is everything
and I really wish for fate to be kind to
you and to walk hand-in-hand with any
dreams you may have. I wish them all to
come to fruition.
It is my sincerest hope that fortune
smiles on you all.
You are all destined to attain great
things. Remember this day, it's a very
important day in your journey.
I say this with all the love and
sincerity I can muster in my heart. I am
so immensely proud of all of you here
today and I am absolutely honored to be
in your distinguished company.
In finishing, I would like to leave you
a poem on your special day.
This poem was read to me every single
day by my mother up until the age of 18.
It is by William Ernest Henley.
And it's called Invictus.
Out of the night that covers me,
black is the pit from pole to pole.
I thank whatever gods there may be
for my unconquerable soul.
In the fell clutch of circumstance, I
have not winced nor cried aloud.
Under the bludgeonings of fate, my head
is bloodied, but unbowed.
Beyond this place of wrath and tears,
looms but the horror of the shade.
And yet the menace of the years shall
find me, and find me unafraid.
It matters not how straight the gate,
how charged with punishments the scroll.
You are the master of your own fate, you
are the captain of your own souls.
You are some of the very best the world
has to offer, and you are now officially
part of a very special community.
Never give up, and always remember it's
about how you make people feel.
May God bless you all,
and may fortune continue to smile on you
all of your days.
As Damon Albarn of Blur famously once
sang in the beautiful ballad Tender,
love is the greatest thing we have.
Hold it dear and close to your heart,
and I really wish you the most fulfilled
and wonderful life. Congratulations,
class of 2024. We all so proud of you
and love you dearly. Congratulations.